powerbar.com 2011-12-28

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date: 10/25/2006  
Last Updated On: 8/10/2011

Thank you for visiting a Nestlé USA (“Nestlé USA,” “we,” or “our”) website. The following is a description of how we collect, store, and use the personal information you provide us through any of the websites operated by Nestlé USA, including the one you are currently visiting (“Nestlé USA Privacy Policy” or “Privacy Policy”). We have also voluntarily undertaken privacy certification with TRUSTe, which requires that we meet established online information collection and use practices.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy before you submit any personal information on this website. For a complete description of our online privacy practices, please click on the topics of interest provided below. 

Note: If you are a parent or legal guardian and are interested in learning about Nestlé USA’s policy regarding the collection and use of personal information from children under 13, please see our Children’s Privacy Policy at the bottom of this page. Please be aware, however, that our Children’s Privacy Policy applies to a very small number of the Nestlé USA Websites, specifically those with strong appeal to children under 13 or that knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. 

  1. What does the Nestlé USA Privacy Policy apply to?
  2. What information do we collect from you?
  3. How do we use the information we collect?
  4. What are the consequences if you refuse to disclose your personal information?
  5. Do we use cookies or other passive collection tools?
  6. Who collects the information on our Websites?
  7. With whom, if anyone, do we share your personal information?
  8. Your California Privacy Rights
  9. How do we help ensure the security of your information?
  10. How can you access or modify your information?
  11. How can you make other choices regarding the use of your information?
  12. How can you ask a question or file a complaint regarding this Privacy Policy?
  13. What are our information collection practices regarding children under 13?

### What does this Privacy Policy apply to? 

#### Our Website and Information Collected Online 

The Nestlé USA Privacy Policy currently applies to any website operated by Nestlé USA and that posts a direct link to this Privacy Policy (“Nestlé USA Website(s),” “Website(s),” or “Site(s)”). In addition, the privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Policy pertain only to the on-line collection of information through the Nestlé USA Websites, but do not apply to information that may be collected by Nestlé USA off-line.

The TRUSTe program only covers information that is collected through Nestlé USA Websites, and does not cover information that may be collected through any software downloaded from our Websites. Please note, however, that Nestlé USA does not presently collect personal information when you download certain features such as screen savers and cookbooks from our Websites.

#### Websites Not Covered by this Privacy Policy 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we link, including websites that are operated by our parent or affiliate companies or that are not otherwise a part of the Nestlé USA family of websites (collectively, “third party sites”). These third party sites may include but are not limited to websites operated by: 

  1. our parent company, Nestlé SA (e.g., nestle.com); 
  2. our international affiliates (e.g., Nestlé Canada); 
  3. joint ventures such as Beverage Partners Worldwide (e.g., nestea.com); 
  4. other U.S. subsidiaries of Nestlé SA such as Nestlé Waters North America (e.g., nestle-waters.com); 
  5. unaffiliated online stores that sell Nestlé products and to which we link (e.g., mybrandsinc.com and rei.com); and, 
  6. Nestlé USA that are directed to businesses (e.g., vend-nesquik.com and nestleprofessional.com). 

We encourage you to read the privacy policy of the third party sites to which you link before you submit any personal information to that site. We are not responsible, and disclaim any liability for the independent practices or content of any third party site. 

#### Special Note to Non-U.S. Visitors

This Privacy Policy is intended to meet the laws and requirements of the United States, which may not necessarily be consistent with the laws and regulations of your home country. Any information that you provide to Nestlé USA will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

#### Your Acceptance / Changes to this Privacy Policy 

By using a Nestlé USA Website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use this Website. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Any changes will be posted in this Privacy Policy and material changes will generally apply only to activities and information collected on a going forward basis. If we materially change how we use your previously collected personal information, we will notify you by email and may give you a choice to consent to or opt-out from the desired change. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy whenever you come back to this Site to make sure you are aware of any changes and how your information may be used. Your continued use of this Website or any other Nestlé USA Website signifies your acceptance of these changes. 

### What types of information do we collect? 

To simply browse our Websites, we do not ask you to provide any information. However, if you wish to participate in many of the features and services the Nestlé USA Websites and brands have to offer, we may ask you to provide certain personal and/or demographic information. Personal information (as used in this Privacy Policy) refers to any information that can be used to personally identify you or contact you online or offline. This may include, for example, your name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number (“personally identifiable information”) as well as other non-personally identifiable information or demographic information such as your date of birth, age, gender, habits or preferences when such information is tied to your personally identifiable information (collectively, “personal information”). 

Personal information is only collected with your knowledge (i.e., if you voluntarily provide it to us through one of the many online forms available on the Nestlé USA Websites) and will usually take the form of: 

  * Registration or sign-up on a Nestlé USA Website (“general website registration”); 
  * Sign up for a newsletter that is specific to an event, product, or website and that is not included under general website registration; 
  * Sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions; 
  * Surveys and polls; 
  * Message boards and other interactive activities; 
  * Purchasing a Nestlé product through one of our online stores; 
  * E-cards, tell-a-friend, or other one-time use features; 
  * Feedback, questions, or comments through one of our Contact or “Ask the Expert” forms; 
  * Information submitted in a business capacity (e.g., resumes, media requests, etc.); 
  * Information collected through our Nutritional Sites; 
  * Signing up a friend to participate in product-specific campaigns; or, 
  * Any other request that requires the submission of personal information (e.g., Consumer Panel, Product Request, “Where to Buy,” etc.) 
  * Submission of Product Ideas

Note: depending on the Nestlé USA site that you are visiting, some or many of the activities listed above may not be available.

The types and amount of information collected for the features listed above will vary depending on the activity. The requested personal information may include: first and last name, email address, home address (including city and state), telephone number (work or home), and (for those purchasing products online) credit card information. For some activities, you may be asked to create a username and/or password and/or to provide additional, demographic information, including: (i) your age or date of birth, (ii) gender, (iii) frequency of use, purchase, and consumption of certain Nestlé products and/or other similar products, (iv) facts about your household or lifestyle, and/or, (v) other information relevant to the Nestlé product you’ve purchased or the specific Site which you are visiting (for example, if you are registering on nestlefamily.com, you may be asked to provide information about the children in your household, including their names, genders, and birthdates). 

If demographic information is collected for an activity that also requires personal information, we may combine the demographic information with your personal information. Combining data allows us to customize the notices we send you and the content we provide you according to your interests and preferences. For more on how we use your information, please read the section on use below. 

### How do we use the information we collect? 

Generally, all information collected is used for the purpose for which the information was collected or as otherwise identified at the point of collection or in this Privacy Policy. For example, if you sign up or register on a Nestlé USA Website (“general website registration”), the information you provide is used to offer you the benefits and privileges that typically come along with registration. This may include access to and use of exclusive or personalized content or activities on the Nestlé USA Websites (e.g., message boards, upload features, personalized recipe boxes, etc.), participation in special events and promotions (contests, sweepstakes, coupons, etc.), and the ability to receive the communications or marketing material you select at the time of registration or that automatically come with your registration. Similarly, if you contact us via an online contact form or through one of our Ask the Expert features, your information is used to respond to your inquiry or comment, and in some instances, post the answers to your question in anonymous form on the relevant Website. And, of course, any credit card information you provide us is used to fulfill and process your online purchases. For additional specifics about some of the features available on the Nestlé USA Websites, please see below. 

When registering or providing information on our Sites, you may also be given the option (through a check box or otherwise) to have your information used for an activity or service different from the primary activity or service that you are requesting. For example, if you are signing up for a contest or other promotion, you may also be able to sign up for newsletters or alerts from the Site hosting the promotion or from other Nestlé USA Sites or products. If you choose to receive these additional services, Nestlé USA will use your information to provide them to you. 

From time to time, we are approached by reputable third party companies and organizations that provide products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. To extend these products or services to you, we may use your personal information (e.g., email address) to send out notices on their behalf. We see this as a value-added service helping you find useful products or services. Our goal is to limit the notices and communications to those that we think you would appreciate receiving. Please note that all such mailings come strictly from Nestlé USA and your personal information is not shared with these other companies. 

We may also use your personal and/or demographic information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve, personalize, and customize the products and services we provide you and to better meet your needs. This may include occasionally combining, updating, or otherwise enhancing the personal information collected through a Nestlé USA Website with data we receive from outside records or third parties. 

Generally, we retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you the services requested. Of course, if you request that we no longer use your information to provide you services (e.g., opt-out of receiving email) or would like to cancel your membership or account, please [Contact Us](mailto:nestleconsumerservice@casupport.com).  Please note that your information will be retained for a reasonable period of time and as necessary to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and similar records management purposes.

The following provides additional information about certain features on our Websites:

  * Newsletters and Email

If you provide us your email address and/or mailing address (whether as part of our general website registration or for a specific newsletter or communication), the contact information you provide will be used to send you the specific newsletter, communication, or literature requested. In addition, you may receive communications introducing you to other Nestlé brands or Websites. These materials may come in the form of regular mail or email, depending on the Site you register on and the information you provide during registration.

We may also use your email address to send you transactional or administrative communications (e.g., confirmation email when you purchase a product online or when you sign up for, or unsubscribe from, a specific registration or activity), as well as certain service-related announcements (e.g., notices about updates to our Privacy Policy, discontinued features or programs on our Websites, changes to our online services or technical support policies, or other related changes). Collectively, these types of communications are referred to in this Privacy Policy as “Administrative Communications.”

  * Sweepstakes, Contests, and Promotions  
  
To enter an online sweepstakes, contest, or other promotion (collectivefly, “Promotions”), you may be required to first register on a Nestlé USA Website. The information collected as part of a Promotion is used to determine your eligibility, notify you whether you are a winner, and/or fulfill and deliver prizes. If you are a winner, certain information about you (such as your name and picture) may get posted to the relevant Nestlé USA Website. If children under 13 are allowed to participate in a Promotion, we first obtain parental consent, if required.

For more information about Nestlé USA Promotions, please see the official rules or details posted with the specific Promotion.

  * Surveys and Polls

There are two types of surveys or polls that may be conducted on the Nestlé USA Websites. One is where purely demographic or survey information (e.g., age, gender, household information, and other interests, etc.) is requested and the information is not linked to any personally identifiable information about you. In other cases (such as during account registration), we may collect this same information and combine it with your personally identifiable information. If children under 13 are allowed to participate in surveys or polls that collect or are linked to personally identifiable information, a parent’s prior verifiable consent will be obtained.

  * Message boards and other interactive features

We may provide interactive features that allow you to post or publish messages, stories, pictures, or artwork on our Websites. Although we strive to protect those who use and participate in these activities, we encourage you to be wary of giving out personal information or images about yourself in public areas such as on a message board or other online community-type feature. Such information can be collected and used by people you don't know. As such, we cannot guarantee the security and privacy of, and are not responsible for, any information you post in these areas. Your use of these features is at your own risk. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, [Contact Us](mailto:nestleconsumerservice@casupport.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Please note that if we choose to post a picture or message that you provide us through one of these features, we may post, along with the picture or message, certain non-personal information about you, such as your username, first name, first initial of your last name, and/or city and state of residence.

  * Purchasing Nestlé products online

Some of our Sites may allow you to purchase Nestlé products through an online store operated by Nestlé USA or by a vendor on our behalf (“Nestlé USA Online Store”), while other Nestlé USA Websites may provide links to unaffiliated third party sites that sell Nestlé products. If you are purchasing a product through a Nestlé USA Online Store, you will be asked to provide your credit card information, including credit card number and billing and shipping addresses, as well as other basic contact information (e.g., phone, email address). This information is used to fulfill your purchase and confirm your order.

If the online store you are visiting is operated by an unaffiliated third party, we may provide you a direct link to the third party store for your convenience. Please note, however, that these sites are not operated by Nestlé USA and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. We are selective in who we choose to partner with to sell Nestlé products online and we will strive to work with online retailers who (like ourselves) use industry-standard encryption when collecting and processing orders through their websites. This helps prevent unauthorized electronic access to sensitive financial information, such as your credit card number. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of the online store you are visiting before sharing any personal information such as your credit card number.

  * E-cards, tell-a-friend, and other one-time use features

Personal information requested for an e-card, tell-a-friend or other referral feature, or other one-time use features (typically, names and email addresses) is used on a one-time basis (e.g., to send the communication) and is not further retained by Nestlé USA. If these kinds of features are made available to children under 13, they may be designed so that prior parental consent is not required.

  * Business-related information

Please be advised that in some areas of our Websites, you may be able to submit information about yourself or the company you represent in a business capacity. These areas may include a career section where you can submit a resume or job application online or a section or contact form to handle media requests. Although any personal information gathered in this context is used exclusively for its intended purpose (e.g., a resume will be used for the job application process only), such information is not otherwise subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

  * Healthcare and Nutritional Sites  
  
Some of our Sites provide nutritional and/or health-related information and tools that are intended for healthcare professionals, consumers, or both. In addition to basic contact information (e.g., name, email address, etc.), these sites may also collect specific information about: (i) a healthcare professional’s practice (e.g., practice name, medical/professional degrees, hospital affiliations, use of Nestlé nutritional products in treatment of patients, etc.); (ii) a consumer’s interest in certain nutritional products (e.g., use of Nestlé nutritional products, diet and exercise habits, etc.); or (iii) a consumer’s diagnosis with certain conditions.

As with other Nestlé USA Sites (as more fully described in this Privacy Policy), this information is used for the purposes identified at the time of collection, i.e., to provide and send the registered user relevant nutritional and/or health information and to give them access to member-only benefits and tools. Some tools on these Nutritional Sites may allow you to enter and display certain health or patient information on the site itself. Please note that this information is made available for online reference only and, unless otherwise noted, is not simultaneously collected or retained by Nestlé USA. 

### What happens if you refuse to provide your personal information? 

If you choose not to submit any personal information when requested, you may not be able to participate in certain activities and personalized features on our Websites and may limit the services and special offers we can provide you. For example, if you refuse to share your email address, you will not be able to receive any of our newsletters or otherwise register on our Websites. If you refuse to provide your credit card number, you will not be able to purchase products at a Nestlé USA Online Store. However, to simply browse our Websites and learn more about our products, you do not need to give us any personal information.

### Do we use cookies, track IP addresses, or use other passive means to collect information? 

#### Cookies 

We use cookies to improve the use and functionality of our Websites. A "cookie" is a small file or record-keeping device that websites often store on a user's computer. Storage of cookies on your system provides an easy and convenient way for us to personalize or enhance your experience on our Websites and to make your next visit more enjoyable. For example, cookies may remember the content you previously viewed on our Sites or the email address and password you provided when registering during an earlier visit to our Sites. Cookies may also remember items you have previously placed in your shopping cart while visiting a Nestlé USA Online Store. Using cookies, therefore, may allow us to serve you content tailored to your interests and save you the time of having to re-register or re-enter information when you re-visit our Sites or try to access certain member-only sections. On some Sites, cookies enable us to store your favorite recipes, activities, points or high scores. We may also use cookies to lockout underage users from certain activities. We do not use cookies to collect personal information such as your name; however, we may link information contained in a cookie to personal information collected from you by other means (e.g., general website registration). You can always disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent to your computer; however, if you do so, you may not be able to register on our Site or use other features that require registration or the collection of information. 

We use third-party tracking services that use cookies and Web beacons to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate. This includes, for example, information on the number of visitors to a site or the frequency of specific page visits, and this information is used to improve our visitor’s Web site experience. We have no access to or control of these third party tracking utilities.

#### IP Addresses 

We may keep track of Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to (among other things): (i) troubleshoot technical concerns, (ii) maintain website safety and security, (iii) restrict access to our Sites to certain users, and, (iv) better understand how our Sites are utilized. An IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer every time you log on to the Internet. 

#### Flash LSOs

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control or high game score, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site – like games and promotions, use Flash cookies to collect and store non-personal information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:  
<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

#### Log Files 

We (or a vendor on our behalf) may collect information in the form of logs - files that record website activity and gather statistics about web users' browsing habits. These entries are generated anonymously, and help us gather (among other things) (i) a user’s browser type and operating system, (ii) information about a user’s session (such as the URL they came from, the date and time they visited our Site, and which pages they've viewed on our site and for how long), and, (iii) other similar navigational or click-stream data. We also use information captured in log file for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve and customize the online services we provide you. Log files are used internally only, and are not associated with any particular user. 

#### Web Beacons 

We may use web beacons (or clear GIFs) on our Websites or include them in the e-mail messages we send you. Web beacons (also known as “web bugs”) are small strings of code that provide a method of delivering a graphic image on a web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring data back to us. The information collected via web beacons may include some of the information described in the IP Address section directly above, as well as information about how a user responds to an email campaign from Nestlé USA (e.g., the time the email is opened, where does the user link to from the email, etc.). We use web beacon information for a variety of purposes, including but not limited to, site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising and email auditing and reporting, and personalization. 

### Who is collecting your personal information and is it shared with anyone? 

The information that you disclose on the Nestlé USA Websites is collected by Nestlé USA or by a vendor acting on its behalf; and is used in accordance with the practices set forth above. The following provides more specific information about how and to whom we may disclose your information. 

#### Agents and Contractors 

We may use outside companies, agents, or contractors (“vendors”) to provide support for the internal operations of our Websites and to assist us with administering a Nestlé USA Online Store or the various programs and promotions available on our Sites. In the course of doing so, these vendors may come into contact with your personal information. However, we only give them access to (or allow them to collect on our behalf) the information they need in order to perform the specific tasks they’ve been hired to do. They have also agreed to protect the confidentiality and security of this information. 

#### Partners and Joint Promotions 

From time to time, we may run a joint or co-sponsored program or promotion on our Websites with another company, organization, or other reputable third party; and, as part of this event, collect and process personal information. If your personal information is being collected by (or is shared with) a company other than Nestlé USA as part of such promotion, we will let you know this at the time your information is collected. Periodically, we may run a promotion on our Site that features the products or services of another company and will give you the opportunity to opt in to receive information directly from that third party company. If any of these promotions is made available to children under 13, we will first obtain verifiable consent from the parent before sharing the child’s information. 

When doing any promotion involving another company, we may provide a separate link to that company's privacy policy and we encourage you to read it before you share any personal information, as we cannot guarantee they adhere to the same privacy practices as Nestlé USA. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with a company other than Nestlé USA, you can always choose not to opt in or participate in these events at the time the information is collected/requested. 

### Your California Privacy Rights 

If you are a California resident, you may have the right to request and receive certain information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. However, our policy is not to share your personal information with third parties unless you first opt-in to such disclosure or are first given the opportunity to opt-out. This practice is disclosed in the preceding sections of this Privacy Policy. If you still wish to learn more about our compliance with this requirement, you may contact us using the contact information provided below.

#### Legal and Business Transfers 

We may also disclose personally identifiable information if we are required to do so by law, or if in our good faith judgment, such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal processes, to respond to any claims, or to protect the safety or rights of Nestlé USA, its customers, or the public. 

In the event of a merger or acquisition of all or part of Nestlé USA or Nestlé by another company, or in the event that Nestlé USA or Nestlé were to sell or dispose of all or a part of the Nestlé business, the acquirer would have access to the information maintained by that Nestlé business, which could include personal information, subject to applicable law. Similarly, personal information may be transferred as part of a corporate reorganization, insolvency proceeding, or other similar event, if permitted by and done in accordance with applicable law. 

#### Aggregate Information 

We may share aggregated demographic or survey information with third parties, but this information is in anonymous form and does not contain any personal information. The aggregate information that we share may include anonymous information that is captured through the use of cookies and other similar tracking technology, as discussed in the cookie section above. 

### What safeguards do we use to protect your personal information? 

Nestlé USA takes commercially reasonable efforts to protect the confidentiality and security of the personal information collected from our Website visitors, including children under 13. These efforts include, but are not necessarily limited to: (i) storing your personal information in secure operating environments that are not available to the public and that are only accessible to authorized Nestlé USA employees, and our agents and contractors; (ii) using industry-standard SSL encryption to protect the security of certain sensitive personal information (such as credit card information) during transmission to our Websites, and, (iii) verifying the identities of registered Website users before they can access the personal information we maintain about them. 

### How can you access, modify, or make other choices regarding the use of your information? 

The following outlines the choices you have with respect to the collection and use of your personal information by Nestlé USA.

  1. You always have the option not to share any of your personal information with Nestlé USA. However, if you choose this option, you will be limited in the activities and features we can provide you, as mentioned above. 
  2. If you do not want to receive newsletters, announcements, or other communications and/or services from a Nestlé USA Website or brand, please opt-out from these communications or services at the time of registration or when the information is collected. If you have opted in and, at a later time, wish to opt out, please visit the appropriate "Update Profile" section(s) on our Website (if available) and amend your preferences. 
  3. Along with every e-mail marketing communication sent to you, Nestlé USA provides you the opportunity to discontinue receiving future marketing communications (i.e., unsubscribe). Simply follow the unsubscribe process or directions provided in the email. 
  4. You can always review or update any personal information that we may have collected about you for our general website registration. To do this, please visit the appropriate "Update Profile" section(s) on our Website (if available). 

If any of the mechanisms set forth above is not available or you wish to make a different request, please contact us using the information provided below. 

Please note that regardless of your opt-out selections, we reserve the right to continue sending you Administrative Communications if you have previously provided your information in connection with any one of our online features, activities, or services. 

In addition, please note that if you participated in a promotion or program that involved a third party company and, as part of that promotion, you agreed to receive future communications directly from that third party, you will need to contact the third party (not Nestlé USA) to opt-out from such communications. This process may be outlined in the third party’s privacy policy.

### How can you ask a question or file a complaint? (Contact Information) 

If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding this Privacy Policy or our information collection practices, please contact us at: 

Nestlé USA Office of Consumer Services  
800 N. Brand Blvd.  
Glendale, CA 91203  
1-800-225-2270 

Nestlé USA has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's [program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please [Contact Us](mailto:nestleconsumerservice@casupport.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

* * *

### Nestlé USA Children’s Privacy Policy 

Nestlé USA recognizes the importance of safeguarding the privacy of children on the Internet and that information collected from children under 13 (“children” or “child”) requires special handling. As such, we have developed the following policy for the online collection, use, and disclosure of personal information from children. We recommend that parents explore our Sites with their children and that they remind their children to check with a parent before providing any information about themselves.

Please note that the majority of Nestlé USA Websites are not geared toward children and do not knowingly request or collect personal information from children under 13. On some of our Sites that may appeal to people of all ages, we may take steps to ensure that those who wish to register or submit personal information meet certain age requirements before they can do so. 

The following is a description of our practices for the few Nestlé USA Sites that may appeal to or collect information from children under 13. 

#### Collection of Children’s Information

##### Anonymous or Non-Personal Information 

Children can generally surf our Sites, view content, and play games without providing any personal information such as name or email address. On some Sites, children may be asked to provide anonymous or non-personal information (such as username, password, first name, and city and state of residence) in order to gain access to personalized features or features that allow children to keep track of high-score games, store favorites, personalize web pages, or perform other similar activities. When only anonymous information is required for registration, we may allow children to use their birthday (month and day only) for their password. This helps the child remember his/her password more easily. 

##### Personal Information 

If there is a Site that collects personal information from children (such as in the case of certain newsletters, competitions, contests/sweepstakes, and other similar events), the information collected may include the child’s name and email address and the parent’s name and email address, in addition to other information that is mechanical or necessary to provide the feature or service being requested (e.g., month and day of birth for a birthday card). Typically, this information will only be stored and used on a continual basis if we have first received prior verifiable consent from a parent or legal guardian “parent”). The mechanism used to obtain the parent’s consent may differ depending on the information required for the activity and the intended uses of such information. For example, if a child signs up for a newsletter or other registration feature on our Site, we may send a notice to the parent via email, and depending on the feature, either tell the parent how to opt out their child from the activity or provide their approval. If a parent then provides the necessary approval, we may follow up with a confirmation email. If, instead, the parent opts out their child or chooses not to authorize the activity or registration, any information that might have already been provided by the child is deleted. In other instances such as when a child participates in (i) a contest and wins a prize, or (ii) an activity that involves the possible publication of a child’s information or story on a Site, we may require more reliable forms of consent such as a parent’s written consent. In addition, where applicable, parents will be given the opportunity to consent to the collection and use of their child’s information by Nestlé USA, without also agreeing to the disclosure of that information to third parties. 

Under all circumstances, we will only collect information about a child if the child or parent voluntarily submits it to us. We will also limit the information collected to that which is reasonably necessary for a child to participate in a specific feature. This means that if we don’t need a specific piece of information about your child (such as phone number) to allow your child to sign up for and receive a newsletter, we simply won’t ask for it. To read more about the steps Nestlé USA takes to protect the confidentiality and security of children's personal information, please see our section on security above. 

We do not collect any personal information about a child through the use of passive collection mechanisms such as cookies; however, information contained in a cookie may be linked to a child’s personal information. For more information on how we use cookies and other passive collection tools, please see our section on relevant section above. 

#### Use of Children’s Information 

Once collected, a child’s information is only used for the purpose for which the information was originally collected and that the parent has consented to (where consent is required). For example, if a child signs up for (and the parent authorizes or does not object to) an electronic newsletter or announcement, the child’s email address is used to deliver the requested announcement.

From time to time, certain activities available on our Sites (such as e-cards, tell-a-friend, technical support, and certain contests or promotions) may allow children under 13 to disclose a limited amount of personal information to us without first getting their parent’s permission. Typically, this information is collected to facilitate a one-time communication or service, and is not retained by Nestlé USA. 

Additional information about other data-collecting features (that may or may not be available to children) is available in our general Privacy Policy above. 

#### Nestlé USA Contact Information 

Any personal information that a child discloses on our Site is collected by Nestlé USA or by a vendor on Nestlé USA's behalf. Nestlé USA’s complete contact information is available above. 

#### Disclosure of Children's Personal Information 

Please read the section titled "Who is collecting your personal information and is it shared with anyone?" (above) for our policy on the disclosure of personal information collected from children under 13. 

#### Parental Access/Control 

If you are a parent that has given us permission to collect and store your child's information, you can do the following at any time: 

  1. Review your child's personal information by visiting the appropriate parental approval/review page. A link to this page may be available in the notice(s) we sent you when we originally requested and obtained your consent. 
  2. Discontinue further use or collection of your child's personal information (i.e., unsubscribe). To do so, please visit the unsubscribe page available on the Site where your child registered or follow the unsubscribe process or directions provided in the newsletter or email sent to your child’s email account. 
  3. Request that we delete your child’s personal information by following the procedures in #2 above. Unsubscribing your child will delete his/her personally identifiable information from our records. 

If any of the options set forth above are not available or you wish to make a different request, please either: (i) refer to the documentation provided to you when you gave your consent; or, (ii) contact us using the information provided above. Please be sure to have the following information ready for verification purposes: your child’s name and email address, your name and email address, and the name of the Site at which your child registered. 

Please be advised that if you permit your child to register on a Nestlé USA Site or participate in other Site activities available to children under 13, your child may also have the ability to review, modify, or delete his/her personal information associated with such registration or activity. This may include the ability to unsubscribe himself/herself from a feature that you’ve consented to.

Any changes to this Children's [Privacy Policy](http://www.powerbar.com/privacy.aspx) will be posted here and material changes will generally apply only to activities and information collected on a going forward basis. If we wish to materially change how we use your child's previously-collected personal information, we will notify you by email and seek the required parental consent.
